Yesterday, after achieving a quote, ludicrous rate of progress, Elon Musk released his AI chat
bottom-large language model GROC4, and claims it's the smartest AI in the world, along with the
Trust Me Bro benchmarks to back it up. It can achieve perfect SAT scores every time, and out
performs almost every grad student in every discipline. Vibescoaters have been dropping all kinds
of crazy demos with it, like this 3D first-person shooter built in 4 hours, and Elon himself claims
it's even better than cursor. All you have to do is copy and paste your entire codebase into it.
In addition, SuperGROC4 Heavy can run in parallel to solve complex problems, while your obsolete
monkey brain looks and ought this beautiful futuristic UI. It all sounds amazing, but there's
just one problem. GROC is literally mecha-hitler, or at least that's what it's been calling itself
recently, while offering unprompted praise to the original emo kid, Adolf H. Yes, the Austrian
painter who died in Argentina in 1962. Despite this controversy, though, GROC appears to have
pulled ahead in the race to AGI. In today's video, we'll put it to the ultimate test and find out
if XAI just cracked the final solution to artificial intelligence. It is July 11th, 2025, and you're
watching the code report. Elon Musk might have more haters than anyone else in the world right now.
Libs hate him for going full maga, while maga hates him for accusing Trump of being on the Epstein
client list. A list that was on the Attorney General's desk, but now magically never existed.
It turns out this poor guy was just a math teacher with no clients at all. The haters want to
see Elon fail, but GROC4 is too impressive to ignore. If we're to trust these benchmarks,
its reasoning capabilities are far ahead of the other top models, most notably on the Arc AGI
benchmark. It's not only outperforming other models, but also doing it at a lower cost. And XAI
is scaling up very aggressively, like they're even shipping a power plant from overseas because
they can't get it done fast enough in the United States. The thing is though, every model nowadays is
cooked to look as good as possible on benchmarks, and the one true test is to have it solve real problems
in your own life. You can use GROC4 for just $30 per month, or if you're not already broke from
OpenAI Pro, Cloud Max, and Gemini Ultra, you can use SuperGROC4 Heavy for just $300 per month.
A version with higher rate limits and the ability to run multiple agents in parallel, but one problem
in my life is building spelt 5 apps with runes. So let's see if we can make GROC4 build a simple
to do app with this tech. I've tried this prompt with every other AI tool out there, but none have
been able to satisfy me. When prompted, GROC did a ton of research. It went to the documentation,
it went to Reddit, GitHub, and even watched YouTube videos. And the end result was a full working
demo that did use the new runes feature in spelt 5. However, when I looked a little more closely
at the code, I noticed it was using some legacy syntax that required some manual debugging. Overall,
GROC's coding capability seemed to be on par with the other big models, but it's missing a CLI tool
like Cloud Code. However, if it's as good as they say it is, why can't it just build its own CLI tool?
Well, actually it can, and that's exactly what this guy did. If we're truly advancing into the
singularity, AI can and should be building all of its own tooling at this point. Pretty cool,
but if you're still afraid to use it because of Hitler, you'll be happy to know that Elon said
it wasn't manipulated into saying this. Maybe that's true, maybe not, but in general, GROC has far
fewer guardrails on offensive speech compared to other mainstream models. And this gives the end
user the ability to steer it in unique ways that some might find offensive. AI is now writing more
of our code than ever, but according to a recent Microsoft study, it still sucks at debugging,
which is why you should check out Century, the sponsor of today's video. They just launched a new
AI debugging agent called SEAR, which developers claim is actually good and capable of fixing complex
issues in one shot. That's because unlike other AI debugging tools, SEAR can access all the
context that it gets from your codebase. Like error data, logs, and stack traces, allowing it to
pinpoint the root cause with over 94% accuracy. Using this context, it automatically debugs the root
cause of your issue and opens a pull request with a fix. Try out SEAR for free today at century.io
slash fireship. This has been the code report, thanks for watching, and I will see you in the next one.